Guide to the Stanford University, Press, Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Press, photographs
1924-1976
1924-1945
PC0093
Stanford University. Press.
2.25 Linear feet
Collection includes photographs, 1936-1945, and one scrapbook, 1924-1976. Subjects of the photographs are the Stanford University Press and staff; Stanford University buildings, students, and faculty/staff; and San Francisco's skyline and bay bridge. Of note among the Stanford photographs are scenes of army training during World War II, the 1942 commencement, the Flying Indians (student flying club), class and laboratory scenes, and a radio workshop ca. 1940. Individuals include John Borsdamm, Will Friend, Herbert Hoover, Marchmont Schwartz, Clark Shaughnessy, Graham Stuart, and Ray Lyman Wilbur. The album pertains largely to staff in the press bindery and includes photographs, clippings, letters, notes, humorous pencil sketches, and poems, mostly by Carlton L. Whitten.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer from the Stanford University Press, 2000.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes photographs, 1936-1945, and one scrapbook, 1924-1976. Subjects of the photographs are the Stanford University Press and staff; Stanford University buildings, students, and faculty/staff; and San Francisco's skyline and bay bridge. Of note among the Stanford photographs are scenes of army training during World War II, the 1942 commencement, the Flying Indians (student flying club), class and laboratory scenes, and a radio workshop ca. 1940. Individuals include John Borsdamm, Will Friend, Herbert Hoover, Marchmont Schwartz, Clark Shaughnessy, Graham Stuart, and Ray Lyman Wilbur. The album pertains largely to staff in the press bindery and includes photographs, clippings, letters, notes, humorous pencil sketches, and poems, mostly by Carlton L. Whitten.
Access Terms
Borsdamm, John.; Friend, Will A.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Schwartz, Marchmont.; Shaughnessy, Clark.; Stanford University. Press.; Stuart, Graham Henry, 1886-1983.; Whitten, Carlton L.; Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Albums.; Photonegatives; Photoprints.; San Francisco (Calif.); San Francisco-Oakland Bay Bridge (Oakland and San Francisco, Calif.); World War, 1939-1945--California--Stanford.
Collection Contents
- Press Images
  - Borsdamm, John (print and negative), 93.001 (Box 1)
  - Croonquist, Stanley (negative), 93.002 (Box 1)
  - Cutter (negative), 93.003 (Box 1)
  - Elwood (?) (print and negative), 93.004 (Box 1)
  - Folder (negative), 93.005 (Box 1)
  - Friend, Will #1 (print and negative), 93.006 (Box 1)
  - Friend, Will #2 (negative), 93.007 (Box 1)
  - Friend, Will #3 (negative), 93.008 (Box 1)
  - Goodspeed, Dewey #1 (negative), 93.009 (Box 1)
  - Goodspeed, Dewey #2 (negative), 93.01 (Box 1)
  - Harris offset press #1 (print and negative), 93.011 (Box 1)
  - Harris offset press #2 (negative), 93.012 (Box 1)
  - Lino machine #1 (print and negative), 93.013 (Box 1)
  - Lino machine #2 (negative), 93.014 (Box 1)
  - Lino machine #3 (negative), 93.015 (Box 1)
  - Ludlow, possibly setting type (print and negative), 93.016 (Box 1)
  - Offset press (print), 93.017 (Box 1)
  - Plate room (print and negative), 93.018 (Box 1)
  - Press employees (2 color snapshots), 93.019 (Box 1)
  - Press party #1 (print and negative), 93.02 (Box 1)
  - Press party #2 (print and negative), 93.021 (Box 1)
  - Press party #3 (2 prints and negative), 93.022 (Box 1)
  - Press party #4 (2 prints and negative), 93.023 (Box 1)
  - Press room employees #1 (3 prints and negative), 93.024 (Box 1)
  - Press room employees #2 (2 prints and negative), 93.025 (Box 1)
  - Press room employees, individual portrait #1 (negative), 93.026 (Box 1)
  - Press room employees, individual portrait #2 (negative), 93.027 (Box 1)
  - Press room employees, individual portrait #3 (print and negative), 93.028 (Box 1)
  - Proof room (print and negative), 93.029 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #1 (negative), 93.03 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #2 (negative), 93.031 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #3 (negative), 93.032 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #4 (negative), 93.033 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #5 (negative), 93.034 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #6 (negative), 93.035 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #7 (negative), 93.036 (Box 1)
  - Setting type #8 (negative), 93.037 (Box 1)
  - Sewing machine #1 (negative), 93.038 (Box 1)
  - Sewing machine #2 (negative), 93.039 (Box 1)
  - Staff group with Christmas tree (print and negative), 93.04 (Box 1)
  - Stitcher (negative), 93.041 (Box 1)
  - Two staff at machine (print and negative), 93.042 (Box 1)
- Stanford Images
  - Administration building #1, 1945 (print and negative), 93.043 (Box 1)
  - Administration building #2 (negative), 93.044 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #1 [men marching in field] (negative), 93.045 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #2 [Army band] (negative), 93.046 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #3 [men with artillery] (negative - damaged), 93.047 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #4 [parade formation] (negative), 93.048 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #5 [civilians in gas masks] (negative), 93.049 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #6 [start of a foot race] (negative), 93.05 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #7 [parade formation] (negative), 93.051 (Box 1)
  - Army training 1940s #8 [start of a foot race] (negative), 93.052 (Box 1)
  - Art class at Red Barn #1 (print), 93.053 (Box 1)
  - Art class at Red Barn #2 (print), 93.054 (Box 1)
  - Art class at Red Barn #3 (print), 93.055 (Box 1)
  - Art class at Red Barn #4 (print), 93.056 (Box 1)
  - Art class behind Memorial Church (2 prints and negative), 93.057 (Box 1)
  - Art Gallery (print and negative), 93.058 (Box 1)
  - Athletics, women's diving #1 (negative), 93.059 (Box 1)
  - Athletics, women's diving #2 (negative), 93.06 (Box 1)
  - Athletics, women's track and field (negative), 93.061 (Box 1)
  - Athletics, women's golf (negative - damaged), 93.062 (Box 1)
  - Athletics, women's tennis (negative), 93.063 (Box 1)
  - Bakewell building, on Galvez (print and negative), 93.064 (Box 1)
  - Bar-b-que pit construction #1, 93.065 (Box 1)
  - Bar-b-que pit construction #1=2, 93.066 (Box 1)
  - Boat house #1 (print and negative), 93.067 (Box 1)
  - Boat house #2, from Lathrop Place, 1937 (negative), 93.068 (Box 1)
  - Boat house #3, from Lathrop Place, 1937 (negative), 93.069 (Box 1)
  - Boat house #4 (print), 93.07 (Box 1)
  - Bonfire rally (print and negative), 93.071 (Box 1)
  - Bookstore #1 (print and negative), 93.072 (Box 1)
  - Bookstore #2 (negative), 93.073 (Box 1)
  - Bookstore #3 (print and negative), 93.074 (Box 1)
  - Business, School of, class 1944 (print and negative), 93.075 (Box 1)
  - Business, School of, library (print and negative), 93.076 (Box 1)
  - Campus, aerial view #1 [by Philip B. Welsh, S. Daily], ca. 1940 (print and negative), 93.077 (Box 1)
  - Campus, aerial view #2 ca. 1940 (print and negative), 93.078 (Box 1)
  - Campus view from golf course ca. 1940 #1 (print and negative), 93.079 (Box 1)
  - Campus view from golf course ca. 1940 #2 (print and negative), 93.08 (Box 1)
  - Campus view from Lathrop home 1945 (print and negative), 93.081 (Box 1)
  - Chappie # 1 [Chappie puppet with camera] (negative), 93.082 (Box 1)
  - Chappie # 2 [large man standing, with coffee cup] (negative), 93.083 (Box 1)
  - Chappie # 3 [large man sitting, with coffee cup] (negative), 93.084 (Box 1)
  - Chappie # 4 [photo shoot at Lake Lag] (negative), 93.085 (Box 1)
  - Chappie # 5 [man with Chappie hat in row boat in Lake Lag] (negative), 93.086 (Box 1)
  - Chemistry lab 1944 #1 (print and negative), 93.087 (Box 1)
  - Chemistry lab 1944 #2 (negative), 93.088 (Box 1)
  - Chemistry lab 1944 #3 (negative), 93.089 (Box 1)
  - Class on internal combustion engines #1, 1944 (print and negative), 93.09 (Box 1)
  - Class on internal combustion engines #2, 1944 (negative), 93.091 (Box 1)
  - Class on internal combustion engines #3, 1944 (negative), 93.092 (Box 1)
  - Class with globe #1, 1944 (print and negative), 93.093 (Box 1)
  - Class with globe #2, 1944 (print and negative), 93.094 (Box 1)
  - Class with globe #3, 1944 (negative), 93.095 (Box 1)
  - Clock tower (print), 93.096 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 (in Frost) #1 (print), 93.097 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 (in Frost) #2 (print), 93.098 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – grads and parents at Bookstore (negative), 93.099 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – students filing into Frost (negative), 93.1 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – procession leaving Memorial Church (negative), 93.101 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – procession in Inner Quad (negative), 93.102 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – procession in front of Museum #1 (negative), 93.103 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – procession in front of Museum #2 (negative), 93.104 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – business students waiting in basketball pavilion (negative), 93.105 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – placing wreath at mausoleum (negative), 93.106 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – laying class plate (negative), 93.107 (Box 1)
  - Commencement 1942 – social science grads waiting in basketball pavilion (negative), 93.108 (Box 1)
  - Commencement, Frost, n.d. (negative), 93.109 (Box 1)
  - Commencement, students outside Memorial Church, n.d. (print), 93.11 (Box 1)
  - Daily staff in back shop #1, 1945 (print and negative), 93.111 (Box 1)
  - Daily staff in back shop #2, 1945 (negative), 93.112 (Box 1)
  - Dance, 1945 (print and negative), 93.113 (Box 1)
  - Earthquake 1906, copy negative of Davey image showing rubble in front of Quad with library in background (negative), 93.114 (Box 1)
  - Education building through Quad arch #1, 1943 (print and negative), 93.115 (Box 1)
  - Education building through Quad arch #2 (negative), 93.116 (Box 1)
  - Education building through Quad arch #3 (negative), 93.117 (Box 1)
  - Education building, oblique view of façade #1, 1939 (negative), 93.118 (Box 1)
  - Education building, oblique view of façade #2, 1942 (negative), 93.119 (Box 1)
  - Education building, oblique view of façade #3 (print and negative), 93.12 (Box 1)
  - Education building, oblique view of façade #4 (negative), 93.121 (Box 1)
  - Education building, oblique view of façade #5 (negative), 93.122 (Box 1)
  - Education building, oblique view of façade #6 (negative), 93.123 (Box 1)
  - Education building, view from front arcade #1, 1939 (print and negative), 93.124 (Box 1)
  - Education building, view from front arcade #2 (negative), 93.125 (Box 1)
  - Education building and library, 1940, from Quad roof (negative), 93.126 (Box 1)
  - Education library (2 prints and negative), 93.127 (Box 1)
  - Electrical Engineering labs (print and negative), 93.128 (Box 1)
  - Electrical Engineering faculty and students in labs #1 (print and negative), 93.129 (Box 1)
  - Electrical Engineering faculty and students in labs #2 (print and negative), 93.13 (Box 1)
  - Electrical Engineering faculty and students in labs #3 (negative), 93.131 (Box 1)
  - Electrical Engineering faculty and students in labs #4 (negative), 93.132 (Box 1)
  - Encina Commons (print and negative), 93.133 (Box 1)
  - Encina Hall, residents in lounge (negative), 93.134 (Box 1)
  - Engineering Corner, 1939 (print and negative), 93.135 (Box 1)
  - Engineering Corner, showing labs and clock tower, ca. 1940 (print and negative), 93.136 (Box 1)
  - Flying Indians ? [six men looking at chart beside plane] (print), 93.137 (Box 1)
  - Flying Indians 1942 [group of male students at graduation] (negative), 93.138 (Box 1)
  - Foundry [male students pouring metal into molds] (print), 93.139 (Box 1)
  - Fraternities – Phi Gamma Delta house #1 (print), 93.14 (Box 1)
  - Fraternities – Phi Gamma Delta house #2 (print), 93.141 (Box 1)
  - Fraternities – Sigma Alpha Epsilon house: students changing sign from "Hayes Hall" to "SAE" (print), 93.142 (Box 1)
  - Frost Amphitheater, 1937 (print and negative), 93.143 (Box 1)
  - Geology corner (print and negative), 93.144 (Box 1)
  - Golf course clubhouse 1942 (print and negative), 93.145 (Box 1)
  - Golf course clubhouse 1944 (print and negative), 93.146 (Box 1)
  - Golf course clubhouse n.d. #1 (print and negative), 93.147 (Box 1)
  - Golf course clubhouse n.d. #2 (print and negative), 93.148 (Box 1)
  - Health, School of (print and negative), 93.149 (Box 1)
  - History corner #1 (print and negative), 93.15 (Box 1)
  - History corner #2 (print), 93.151 (Box 1)
  - History corner #3 (print), 93.152 (Box 1)
  - History corner #4 (print), 93.153 (Box 1)
  - History corner with students, ca. 1945 (print and negative), 93.154 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Carillon Bells 1945 #1 (print and negative), 93.155 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Carillon Bells 1945 #2 (negative), 93.156 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Carillon Bells 1945 #3 (negative), 93.157 (Box 1)
  - Hoover House, front view (negative), 93.158 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower 1943 (negative), 93.159 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower 1944 (negative), 93.16 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower 1945 (negative), 93.161 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower n.d. #1 (negative), 93.162 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower n.d. #2 (negative), 93.163 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower n.d. #3 (print and negative), 93.164 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower n.d. #4 (print and negative), 93.165 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower n.d. #5 (print), 93.166 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower n.d. #6 (print), 93.167 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower (black and white transparency), 93.168 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower 1943 (infrared negative), 93.169 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower and Library 1943 #1 (infrared negative), 93.17 (Box 1)
  - Hoover Tower and Library 1943 #2 (infrared negative), 93.171 (Box 1)
  - Knoll, the, 1945 (print and negative), 93.172 (Box 1)
  - Laboratory, working at microscopes #1 (print and negative), 93.173 (Box 1)
  - Laboratory, working at microscopes #2 (print and negative), 93.174 (Box 1)
  - Laboratory, working at microscopes #2 (negative), 93.175 (Box 1)
  - Lagunita Court 1944 (negative), 93.176 (Box 1)
  - Lagunita Court n.d. #1 (print and negative), 93.177 (Box 1)
  - Lagunita Court n.d. #2 (print), 93.178 (Box 1)
  - Lagunita Court entrance 1945 (print and negative), 93.179 (Box 1)
  - Lake Lagunita, with boat house (negative), 93.18 (Box 1)
  - Lasuen Row #1 (print and negative), 93.181 (Box 1)
  - Lasuen Row #2 (print and negative), 93.182 (Box 1)
  - Lasuen Row #3 (print and negative), 93.183 (Box 1)
  - Lasuen Row #4 (print and negative), 93.184 (Box 1)
  - Lasuen Row #5 (print and negative), 93.185 (Box 1)
  - Lasuen Row #6 (negative), 93.186 (Box 1)
  - Library (1919) – n.d. (print), 93.187 (Box 1)
  - Library (1919) – 1938 (negative), 93.188 (Box 1)
  - Library, old medical book #1, 1942 (negative), 93.189 (Box 1)
  - Library, old medical book #2, 1942 (negative), 93.19 (Box 1)
  - Library with Hoover Tower (infrared negative), 93.191 (Box 1)
  - Mausoleum #1 (print and negative), 93.192 (Box 1)
  - Mausoleum #2, detail of sphinx 1940, (negative), 93.193 (Box 1)
  - Medical School class 1944 #1 (print and negative), 93.194 (Box 1)
  - Medical School class 1944 #2 (negative), 93.195 (Box 1)
  - Medical School class 1944 #3 (negative), 93.196 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Auditorium from Quad roof (print and negative), 93.197 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Auditorium (infrared negative), 93.198 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church chancel (print and negative), 93.199 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church exterior #1 (print and negative), 93.2 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church exterior #2 (print and negative), 93.201 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church exterior #3 (print and negative), 93.202 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church exterior #4, 1945 (print and negative), 93.203 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church exterior #5, 1943 (print and negative), 93.204 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #1 (negative), 93.205 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #2 (negative), 93.206 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #3 (negative), 93.207 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #4 (print), 93.208 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #5 (print), 93.209 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #6 (print), 93.21 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #7 (print), 93.211 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church front view #8 (print), 93.212 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church rear view (negative), 93.213 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church side view (print and negative), 93.214 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church 1945 #1 (infrared negative), 93.215 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Church 1945 #2 (infrared negative), 93.216 (Box 1)
  - Military review in front of Quad, 1942 (negative), 93.217 (Box 1)
  - Museum – statue at night 1945 (negative), 93.218 (Box 1)
  - Oak tree with people sitting under it (print and negative), 93.219 (Box 1)
  - Palm Drive, entrance gates 1945 (negative), 93.22 (Box 1)
  - Palm Drive, entrance gates at night 1945 (print and negative), 93.221 (Box 1)
  - Palo Alto University Avenue underpass at night, 1945 (negative), 93.222 (Box 1)
  - Physics Corner #1 (print and negative), 93.223 (Box 1)
  - Physics Corner #2 (negative), 93.224 (Box 1)
  - Post Office (print), 93.225 (Box 1)
  - Quad arcades #1 (print and negative), 93.226 (Box 1)
  - Quad arcades #2 (negative), 93.227 (Box 1)
  - Quad arcades #3 (negative), 93.228 (Box 1)
  - Quad arcades #4 (print and negative), 93.229 (Box 1)
  - Quad arcades #5 (print), 93.23 (Box 1)
  - Quad arches (negative), 93.231 (Box 1)
  - Quad arches detail #1 (print and negative), 93.232 (Box 1)
  - Quad arches detail #2 (print), 93.233 (Box 1)
  - Quad, East Gate #1 (print and negative), 93.234 (Box 1)
  - Quad, East Gate #2 (negative), 93.235 (Box 1)
  - Quad, from Hoover Tower (negative), 93.236 (Box 1)
  - Quad, front view (print and negative), 93.237 (Box 1)
  - Quad, front view with Hoover Tower (print and negative), 93.238 (Box 1)
  - Quad, front view night shot 1945 (print and negative), 93.239 (Box 1)
  - Quad, front view with Palm Drive #1 (negative), 93.24 (Box 1)
  - Quad, front view with Palm Drive #2 1944 (print and damaged negative), 93.241 (Box 1)
  - Quad, Inner (negative), 93.242 (Box 1)
  - Quad, Inner, at night 1945 (damaged negative), 93.243 (Box 1)
  - Quad, side view with students #1 ca. 1943 (negative), 93.244 (Box 1)
  - Quad, side view with students #2 1945 (print and negative), 93.245 (Box 1)
  - Quad, view of roofs from History Corner (print and negative), 93.246 (Box 1)
  - Radio workshop ca. 1940 #1 (print and negative), 93.247 (Box 1)
  - Radio workshop ca. 1940 #2 (print and negative), 93.248 (Box 1)
  - Roble Gym #1 (print and negative), 93.249 (Box 1)
  - Roble Gym #2 (print and negative), 93.25 (Box 1)
  - Roble Gym #3 – interior courtyard (print), 93.251 (Box 1)
  - Roble Hall #1 (print and negative), 93.252 (Box 1)
  - Roble Hall #2 (negative), 93.253 (Box 1)
  - Roble Pool (print), 93.254 (Box 1)
  - Sequoia Hall [original Roble Hall] (print and negative), 93.255 (Box 1)
  - Stadium, aerial view (negative), 93.256 (Box 1)
  - Stanford seal with motto 1943 (multiple negatives), 93.257 (Box 1)
  - Students, ca. 1940 (print and negative), 93.258 (Box 1)
  - Students in Law Library 1944 #1 (negative), 93.259 (Box 1)
  - Students in Law Library 1944 #2 (negative), 93.26 (Box 1)
  - Students in Law Library 1944 #3 (negative), 93.261 (Box 1)
  - Students on Library steps #1 (print and negative), 93.262 (Box 1)
  - Students on Library steps #2 (negative), 93.263 (Box 1)
  - Tile roofs #1 (negative), 93.264 (Box 1)
  - Tile roofs #2 (negative), 93.265 (Box 1)
  - Toyon Hall, exterior detail, 1945 (negative), 93.266 (Box 1)
  - Union, exterior front (print and negative), 93.267 (Box 1)
  - Union, exterior with ivy (print and negative), 93.268 (Box 1)
  - Ventura Hall, 1943 (print and negative), 93.269 (Box 1)
  - Workmen with machinery (negative), 93.27 (Box 1)
- Stanford people
  - Col. Frank R. Allen #1 (negative), 93.271 (Box 1)
  - Col. Frank R. Allen #2 (negative), 93.272 (Box 1)
  - Dean, Everett S. (negative), 93.273 (Box 1)
  - Hoover, Herbert, Fall 1936 – at Hoover House with LHH behind him (negative), 93.274 (Box 1)
  - Schwartz, Marchie 1942 #1 (negative), 93.275 (Box 1)
  - Schwartz, Marchie 1942 #2 (negative), 93.276 (Box 1)
  - Schwartz, Marchie 1942 #3 (negative), 93.277 (Box 1)
  - Sharp, Dr. Stan (negative), 93.278 (Box 1)
  - Shaughnessy, Clark (negative), 93.279 (Box 1)
  - Stewart, Virginia (negative), 93.28 (Box 1)
  - Stuart, Graham #1 (negative), 93.281 (Box 1)
  - Stuart, Graham #2 (negative), 93.282 (Box 1)
  - Stuart, Graham #3 (negative), 93.283 (Box 1)
  - Stuart, Graham #4 (negative), 93.284 (Box 1)
  - Thomas, Lawrence G. (print and negative), 93.285 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, R. L. and Cowden, 1942 #1 (negative), 93.286 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, R. L. and Cowden, 1942 #2 (negative), 93.287 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, R. L. in his office #1 (negative), 93.288 (Box 1)
  - Wilbur, R. L. in his office #2 (negative), 93.289 (Box 1)
  - Woman with a camera, 93.29 (Box 1)
- San Francisco images
  - Bay Bridge and San Francisco skyline 1945 (negative), 93.291 (Box 1)
  - Bay Bridge from ferry 1945 #1 (print and negative), 93.292 (Box 1)
  - Bay Bridge from ferry 1945 #2 (negative), 93.293 (Box 1)
  - Ferry boat and Bay Bridge 1945 (negative), 93.294 (Box 1)
  - San Francisco 1945 (print and infrared negative), 93.295 (Box 1)
  - San Francisco skyline from ferry 1945 #1 (print and negative), 93.296 (Box 1)
  - San Francisco skyline from ferry 1945 #2 (print and negative), 93.297 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous images
  - Clouds, for double printing special effects (negative), 93.298 (Box 1)
  - Leaves (damaged negative), 93.299 (Box 1)
  - Leaves, close-up (negative), 93.3 (Box 1)
  - Monkscloth background (multiple negatives), 93.301 (Box 1)
  - Oak tree bark, close-up (negative), 93.302 (Box 1)
  - Smoke (negative), 93.303 (Box 1)
- Color transparencies (4x5")
  - E – H: Education building, Encina Hall, Golf Course, History Corner, Hoover Tower (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Inner Quad (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - L – O: Library, Museum, Old Union (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Auditorium (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Memorial Church – exterior (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Memorial Church – interior (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Memorial Church – windows and mosaics (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Court and Memorial Court arches (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - P & R: Palm Drive, Physics Corner, Press (photo lithography work), Roble Hall (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Quad – front views and East and West Gates (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Days of Yesterday "Bindery": Album of photographs, clippings, letters, notes, programs, humorous pencil sketches, and poems (mostly by Carlton L. Whitten), 1924-1976. (Box 3)